<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>array on Q. Weng</title>
    <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/tags/array/</link>
    <description>Recent content in array on Q. Weng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 12:16:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://foxisawesome.github.io/tags/array/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>140 Word Break II</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/140-word-break-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 21:26:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/140-word-break-ii/</guid>
      <description>LC 140 Word Break II Given a non-empty string s and a dictionary wordDict containing a list of non-empty words, add spaces in s to construct a sentence where each word is a valid dictionary word. Return all such possible sentences. Input: s = &amp;quot;pineapplepenapple&amp;quot; wordDict = [&amp;quot;apple&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pen&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;applepen&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pine&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pineapple&amp;quot;] Output: [ &amp;quot;pine apple pen apple&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pineapple pen apple&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;pine applepen apple&amp;quot; ] Solution 2020-09-03 Notes: 第一</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>128 Longest Consecutive Sequence</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/128-longest-consecutive-sequence/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 20:41:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/128-longest-consecutive-sequence/</guid>
      <description>LC 128 Longest Consecutive Sequence Given an unsorted array of integers, find the length of the longest consecutive elements sequence. Your algorithm should run in O(n) complexity. Example: Input: [100, 4, 200, 1, 3, 2] Output: 4 Explanation: The longest consecutive elements sequence is [1, 2, 3, 4]. Therefore its length is 4. Solution 2020-09-03 Notes: 题目 time complexity 要求O(N)，那没其</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>543 Diameter of Binary Tree</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/543-diameter-of-binary-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 15:49:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/543-diameter-of-binary-tree/</guid>
      <description>LC 543 Diameter of Binary Tree   Given a binary tree, you need to compute the length of the diameter of the tree. The diameter of a binary tree is the length of the longest path between any two nodes in a tree. This path may or may not pass through the root.
Example: Given a binary tree
 1 / \ 2 3 / \ 4 5  Return 3, which is the length of the path [4,2,1,3] or [5,2,1,3].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>48 Rotate Image</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/48-rotate-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 14:16:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/48-rotate-image/</guid>
      <description>LC 48 Rotate Image   You are given an n x n 2D matrix representing an image, rotate the image by 90 degrees (clockwise).
You have to rotate the image in-place, which means you have to modify the input 2D matrix directly. DO NOT allocate another 2D matrix and do the rotation.
 Solution 2020-09-02T14:16:29-04:00 Notes:
  Algo #1: tranpose the matrix first, then reverse the rows. it requires two passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>528 Random Pick With Weight</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/528-random-pick-with-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 14:11:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/528-random-pick-with-weight/</guid>
      <description>LC 528 Random Pick With Weight   Given an array of positive integers w. where w[i] describes the weight of i``th index (0-indexed).
We need to call the function pickIndex() which randomly returns an integer in the range [0, w.length - 1]. pickIndex() should return the integer proportional to its weight in the w array. For example, for w = [1, 3], the probability of picking index 0 is 1 / (1 + 3) = 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>445 Add Two Num II</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/445-add-two-num-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 09:38:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/445-add-two-num-ii/</guid>
      <description>LC 445 Add Two Num II   You are given two non-empty linked lists representing two non-negative integers. The most significant digit comes first and each of their nodes contain a single digit. Add the two numbers and return it as a linked list.
You may assume the two numbers do not contain any leading zero, except the number 0 itself.
Follow up: What if you cannot modify the input lists?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>295 Find Median From Data Stream</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/295-find-median-from-data-stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 21:33:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/295-find-median-from-data-stream/</guid>
      <description>LC 295 Find Median From Data Stream Median is the middle value in an ordered integer list. If the size of the list is even, there is no middle value. So the median is the mean of the two middle value. For example, [2,3,4], the median is 3 [2,3], the median is (2 + 3) / 2 = 2.5 Solution 2020-09-01 Notes: Follow 了花花酱的so</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>148 Sort List</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/148-sort-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 19:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/148-sort-list/</guid>
      <description>LC 148 Sort List   Sort a linked list in O(n log n) time using constant space complexity.
Example 1:
Input: 4-&amp;gt;2-&amp;gt;1-&amp;gt;3 Output: 1-&amp;gt;2-&amp;gt;3-&amp;gt;4  Example 2:
Input: -1-&amp;gt;5-&amp;gt;3-&amp;gt;4-&amp;gt;0 Output: -1-&amp;gt;0-&amp;gt;3-&amp;gt;4-&amp;gt;5   Solution 2020-09-01 Notes:
 Time Complaxity O(nlogn) indicates merge sort algo. in the sortList, line 8:if not head or not head.next: return head actually returns head not None. slow and fast pointers to divide list into two need a lfet tail pointer: l_tail to cut off left linked list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>79 Word Search</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/79-word-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 16:07:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/79-word-search/</guid>
      <description>LC 79 Word Search   Given a 2D board and a word, find if the word exists in the grid.
The word can be constructed from letters of sequentially adjacent cell, where &amp;ldquo;adjacent&amp;rdquo; cells are those horizontally or vertically neighboring. The same letter cell may not be used more than once.
Example:
board = [ [&#39;A&#39;,&#39;B&#39;,&#39;C&#39;,&#39;E&#39;], [&#39;S&#39;,&#39;F&#39;,&#39;C&#39;,&#39;S&#39;], [&#39;A&#39;,&#39;D&#39;,&#39;E&#39;,&#39;E&#39;] ] Given word = &amp;quot;ABCCED&amp;quot;, return true. Given word = &amp;quot;SEE&amp;quot;, return true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>981 Time Based Key Value Store</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/981-time-based-key-value-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 14:15:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/981-time-based-key-value-store/</guid>
      <description>LC 981 Time Based Key Value Store Create a timebased key-value store class TimeMap, that supports two operations. set(string key, string value, int timestamp) Stores the key and value, along with the given timestamp. get(string key, int timestamp) Returns a value such that set(key, value, timestamp_prev) was called previously, with timestamp_prev &amp;lt;= timestamp. If there are multiple such values, it returns the one with the largest timestamp_prev. If there are</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1041 Robot Bounded in Circle</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/1041-robot-bounded-in-circle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 22:14:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/1041-robot-bounded-in-circle/</guid>
      <description>LC 1041 Robot Bounded in Circle On an infinite plane, a robot initially stands at (0, 0) and faces north. The robot can receive one of three instructions: &amp;quot;G&amp;quot;: go straight 1 unit; &amp;quot;L&amp;quot;: turn 90 degrees to the left; &amp;quot;R&amp;quot;: turn 90 degress to the right. The robot performs the instructions given in order, and repeats them forever. Return true if and only if there exists a circle in</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>957 Prison Cells</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/957-prison-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 19:26:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/957-prison-cells/</guid>
      <description>LC 957 Prison Cells There are 8 prison cells in a row, and each cell is either occupied or vacant. Each day, whether the cell is occupied or vacant changes according to the following rules: If a cell has two adjacent neighbors that are both occupied or both vacant, then the cell becomes occupied. Otherwise, it becomes vacant. (Note that because the prison is a row, the first and the</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>735 Aseroid Collision</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/735-aseroid-collision/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 19:05:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/735-aseroid-collision/</guid>
      <description>LC 735 Aseroid Collision We are given an array asteroids of integers representing asteroids in a row. For each asteroid, the absolute value represents its size, and the sign represents its direction (positive meaning right, negative meaning left). Each asteroid moves at the same speed. Find out the state of the asteroids after all collisions. If two asteroids meet, the smaller one will explode. If both are the same size,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>141 Linked List Cycle</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/141-linked-list-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 21:35:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/141-linked-list-cycle/</guid>
      <description>LC 141 Linked List Cycle Given a linked list, determine if it has a cycle in it. To represent a cycle in the given linked list, we use an integer pos which represents the position (0-indexed) in the linked list where tail connects to. If pos is -1, then there is no cycle in the linked list. Example 1: Input: head = [3,2,0,-4], pos = 1 Output: true Explanation: There</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>328 Odd Even Linked List</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/328-odd-even-linked-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 21:27:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/328-odd-even-linked-list/</guid>
      <description>LC 328 Given a singly linked list, group all odd nodes together followed by the even nodes. Please note here we are talking about the node number and not the value in the nodes. You should try to do it in place. The program should run in O(1) space complexity and O(nodes) time complexity. Example 1: Input: 1-&amp;gt;2-&amp;gt;3-&amp;gt;4-&amp;gt;5-&amp;gt;NULL Output: 1-&amp;gt;3-&amp;gt;5-&amp;gt;2-&amp;gt;4-&amp;gt;NULL linked list 终于在周末刷出感</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1266 Minimum Time Visiting All Points</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/1266-minimum-time-visiting-all-points/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 21:24:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/1266-minimum-time-visiting-all-points/</guid>
      <description>LC 1266 On a plane there are n points with integer coordinates points[i] = [xi, yi]. Your task is to find the minimum time in seconds to visit all points. You can move according to the next rules: In one second always you can either move vertically, horizontally by one unit or diagonally (it means to move one unit vertically and one unit horizontally in one second). You have to</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>530 Min Abs Dif BST</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/530-min-abs-dif-bst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 20:59:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/530-min-abs-dif-bst/</guid>
      <description>LC 530
Given a binary search tree with non-negative values, find the minimum absolute difference between values of any two nodes.
 Given a binary search tree with non-negative values, find the minimum absolute difference between values of any two nodes.
Example:
Input: 1 \ 3 / 2 Output: 1 Explanation: The minimum absolute difference is 1, which is the difference between 2 and 1 (or between 2 and 3).   8/30/2020 Note:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>98 Valid BST</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/98-valid-bst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 20:59:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/98-valid-bst/</guid>
      <description>LC 98 Valid BST Given a binary tree, determine if it is a valid binary search tree (BST). Assume a BST is defined as follows: The left subtree of a node contains only nodes with keys less than the node&amp;rsquo;s key. The right subtree of a node contains only nodes with keys greater than the node&amp;rsquo;s key. Both the left and right subtrees must also be binary search trees. Example</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>701 Insert Into BST</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/701-insert-into-bst/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 20:58:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/701-insert-into-bst/</guid>
      <description>LC 701 Given the root node of a binary search tree (BST) and a value to be inserted into the tree, insert the value into the BST. Return the root node of the BST after the insertion. It is guaranteed that the new value does not exist in the original BST. Note that there may exist multiple valid ways for the insertion, as long as the tree remains a BST</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sliding Window Note</title>
      <link>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/sliding-window-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 17:08:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://foxisawesome.github.io/posts/sliding-window-note/</guid>
      <description>滑动窗口算法的思路是这样： 1、我们在字符串S中使用双指针中的左右指针技巧，初始化left = right = 0，把索引左闭右开区间[left, right)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
